Let's do a quick demo of OpenStack
Unshelver.
So, this is a web app based on FastHTML
that uses GitHub for authentication and
then uses the OpenStack SDK to
communicate with the OpenStack API and
manage pre-existing instances. So
this is meant to be of course deployed
on a server but for testing purposes
I'm just running it locally. So
Once the app is running
we can connect to it on localhost and
then we get redirected to GitHub for
login and after login I'm also
checking for membership to an
organization, which can be configured
in a YAML file.
That YAML file also lists all
different virtual machines that we
can monitor. So I haven't implemented
the shelving feature yet. For now it
only handles the unshelving step.
So we have this instance which is just a
simple web server. It's a Caddy default
deployment. And on top of that I
also implemented the /health endpoint
which returns the JSON .
And so what we can do is
click on Unshelve Start.
So this is useful if you have a service
that you don't need all the time and
so you have a simple interface that you
can spawn that service really quickly
because
an OpenStack instance takes just one
minute or two to unshelve and so after
that it's just time for your
application to start. So it's pretty
efficient. And under the hood,
this uses the OpenStack SDK to
unshelve the instance and then it
checks the health endpoint every 10
seconds to wait for the service to
become available. So you see now the
instance is probably ready. Here it
is. It's ready but the service is not
available yet and we're going to
wait another few seconds
and then here we go. Now the instance
status is active and we can click on
Open Web App to access the service which
in this case is just the Caddy
simple status page but it can be an
LLM deployed with a web UI or some other
useful web services.